WOMAN: Earth-That-Was
could no longer sustain our
numbers, we were so many.
We found a new solar system,
dozens of planets
and hundreds of moons.
Each one terraformed,
a process taking decades,
to support human life.
To be new Earths.
The central planets
formed the Alliance.
Ruled by an
interplanetary parliament,
the Alliance was
a beacon of civilization.
The savage outer planets
were not so enlightened,
and refused Alliance control.
The war was devastating.
But the Alliance's victory
over the Independents
ensured a safer universe.
And now, everyone
can enjoy the comfort
and enlightenment
of true civilization.
Why were the Independents
even fighting us?
Why wouldn't they look
to be more civilized?
I hear they're cannibals.
That's only Reavers.
Reavers aren't real.
Full well they are.
I heard they attack
settlers from space
and kill them,
and wear their skins
and rape them for
hours and hours...
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
It's true that there are
dangers on the outer planets.
So with so many social
and medical advancements
we can bring to
the Independents,
why would they fight
so hard against us?
We meddle.
River?
People don't like
to be meddled with.
We tell them what to
do, what to think.
Don't run,
don't walk.
We're in their homes and in their
heads and we haven't the right.
We're meddlesome.
River, we're not telling
people what to think,
we're just trying
to show them how.
(SCREAMING)
DR. MATHIAS: She's dreaming.
Got that?
Off the charts.
Scary monsters.
Let's amp it up.
Delcium, eight drop.
(PANTING)
See, most of our best work
is done when they're asleep.
We can monitor and direct
their subconscious,
implant suggestions.
It's a little startling
to see at first,
but the results
are spectacular.
Especially in this case.
River Tam is our star pupil.
I've heard that.
She'll be ideal for
defense deployment,
even with the
side effects.
Tell me about them.
Well, obviously,
she's unstable.
The neural stripping
does tend to fragment
their own
reality matrix.
It manifests
as borderline...
What use do we have for a
psychic if she's insane?
(GROANING) DR. MATHIAS:
She's not just a psychic.
Given the right trigger, this
girl is a living weapon.
She has her lucid periods. We're
hoping to improve upon the...
I'm sorry, sir,
but I have to ask.
Is there a reason
for this inspection?
Am I making you nervous?
Key members of Parliament have
personally observed this subject.
I was told that the
Alliance's support
for the project
was unanimous.
The demonstration
of her powers...
How is she physically?
Like nothing
we've seen.
All our subjects are conditioned
for combat, but River,
she's a creature of
extraordinary grace.
Yes.
She always did
love to dance.
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
River, it's Simon.
(MOANING)
Please, it's Simon.
It's your brother.
Simon.
They know you've come.
(MACHINES BEEPING)
We can't make it to the
surface from the inside.
(CLANGING)
Find out.
(GRUNTING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(MACHINERY CLANKING)
MAN: A subject is loose,
security breach. Shaft 7.
(THUDDING)
THE OPERATIVE: Stop.
Backtrack. Stop.
Excuse me,
no one is allowed
in the records room
without my express
permission.
Forgive me, but I prefer to see
the event alone, without
bias.
I need to see
your clearance.
And you are right to insist.
(BEEPING)
AUTOMATED VOICE: Parliamentary override.
Full access.
Apologies.
An operative of
the Parliament
will, of course,
have full cooperation.
I'm not sure what...
I see no listing
of rank or name.
I have neither.
Like this facility,
I don't exist.
Let's talk about
the Tams.
I assume you've scanned
the status logs...
River was your greatest success.
A prodigy.
A phenomenon.
Until her brother walked in
here and took her from you.
It's not quite
so simple.
I'm well aware of that.
There was no way
that I could...
No. No. Of course.
The boy spent
his entire fortune
developing the contacts
to infiltrate this place.
Gave up a brilliant future
in medicine as well.
It's madness.
Madness?
Have you looked at this
scan carefully, Doctor?
At his face?
It's love,
in point of fact.
Something a good deal
more dangerous.
Why are you here?
Because the situation is even
less simple than you think.
Do you know what
your sin is, Doctor?
I wonder if...
It's pride.
Key members of Parliament have
personally observed this subject.
I was told that the
Alliance's support...
"Key members
of Parliament."
Key.
The minds behind
every military,
diplomatic, and
covert operation
in the galaxy,
and you put them
in a room with
a psychic.
(STAMMERING) If there was some
classified information that she...
She never spoke of it.
I don't know what it is.
Nor do I.
And judging by her
deteriorating mental state,
I'd say we're
both better off.
Secrets are not
my concern.
Keeping them is.
Whatever secrets she might
have accidentally gleaned,
it's probable she doesn't
even know she knows them.
That they're buried beneath
layers of psychosis.
You know, in certain older
civilized cultures,
when men failed
as entirely
as you have, they would
throw themselves
on their swords.
Well, unfortunately,
I forgot to bring a sword.
I would put that down
right now, if I were you.
Would you be killed in your
sleep like an ailing pet?
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
THE OPERATIVE: Young miss...
(CLANKING)
Young miss, I'll need all the logs
on behavioral modification triggers.
We'll have to reach
out to River Tam
and help her to
come back to us.
No matter how far
out Simon has...
(CLANKING)
(GASPING)
This is a good death.
There's no shame in this,
in a man's death. A man
who has done fine works.
We're making
a better world.
All of them,
better worlds.
Young miss, I need you
to go to work now.
I think I may have
a long way to travel.
Where are you hiding,
little girl?
(EXPLOSION)
(ALARM BUZZING)
What was that?
Did you see that?
Was that the primary
buffer panel?
It did seem
to resemble...
Did the primary
buffer panel
just fall off my gorramn
ship for no apparent reason?
(RUMBLING)
Looks like.
I thought Kaylee checked
the entry couplings.
I've a clear memory of it.
If she doesn't get us
extra flow from the engine room
to offset the burn-through,
this landing is gonna
get pretty interesting.
Define "interesting."
"Oh, God, we're
all gonna die?"
This is the captain.
We have a little problem
with our entry sequence,
so we may experience some
slight turbulence
and then explode.
Can you shave the vector?
I'm doing it!
It's not enough.
Just get us
on the ground!
That part will happen
pretty definitely.
We're gonna explode?
I don't wanna explode.
Jayne, how many weapons
you plan on taking?
You only got two arms.
I just get excitable
as to choice. Like to
have my options open.
I don't plan on any shooting
taking place during this job.
What you plan and what takes place
ain't ever exactly been similar.
No grenades. No grenades!
Huh? Aw!
We crashing again?
MAL: Talk to your husband.
Mule prepped?
Good to go, sir.
Just loading her up.
Those grenades?
JAYNE: Yeah, Captain doesn't want them.
Jayne, we're robbing the place.
We're not occupying it.
(CRASHING)
Kaylee!
Kaylee, what in the sphincter
of hell are you playing at?
We got the primary buffer
panel coming right...
Everything's shiny,
Captain. Not to fret.
You told me those entry couplings
would hold for another week!
That was six months
ago, Captain.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
My ship don't crash.
If she crashes,
you crashed her.
Doctor.
Guess who needs to get innocked
before we hit planet-side.
(CRASHING)
Bit of a
rockety ride.
Nothing to be
worried about.
I'm not worried.
Fear is nothing to be
ashamed of, Doctor.
This isn't fear.
This is anger.
Well, kind of hard to tell one
from the other, face like yours.
Well, I imagine if it were
fear, my eyes would be wider.
Hmm. I'll keep a lookout
for that next time.
You're not taking her.
No, no, this is not a thing I'm
interested in talking over with...
She's not going with
you, and that's final.
I hear the words "that's final"
come out your mouth ever again,
they truly will be.
This boat is my home. You
all are guests on it.
Guests?
Now, I earned my
passage, Captain...
And it's time your little sister
learned from your example.
I have earned
my passage
(EXPLOSION)
treating bullet holes,
knife wounds, laser burns.
Some of our jobs are more
interesting than others.
And you want to put my sister
in the middle of that.
Didn't say "want."
Said "will."
It's one job, Doc.
She'll be fine.
She's a 17-year-old girl.
A mentally
traumatized 17...
She's a reader.
Sees into the
truth of things.
Might see trouble before it's coming.
Which is of use to me.
And that's your guiding star, isn't it?
What's of use.
(RUMBLING)
Honestly, Doctor, I think we may
really crash this time anyway.
(CLICKING)
Do you understand what
I have gone through
to keep River away
from the Alliance?
I do, and it's a fact we
here have been courteous
enough to keep
to our own selves.
Are you
threatening to...
I look out for
me and mine.
That don't include you
less I conjure it does.
You stuck a thorn in the Alliance's paw.
That tickles me a bit.
But it also means I got to step
twice as fast to avoid them
and that means turning
down plenty of jobs.
Even honest ones.
Put this crew together
with the promise of work,
which the Alliance makes
harder every year.
Come a day there won't be
room for naughty men like us
to slip about at all.
This job goes south, there
well may not be another.
So here is us,
on the raggedy edge.
(METAL CLANKING)
Don't push me,
and I won't push you.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Zoe, Wash gonna straighten this
boat out before we get flattened?
ZOE: Like a downy feather, sir.
No one flies like my mister.
(ENGINE GRINDING)
(MAL AND ZOE CHATTERING)
SIMON: River.
I know. We're
going for a ride.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Hey, little one.
Understand your
part in all this?
Do you?
This is what I do,
darling.
This is what I do.
MAL: Let's move, people.
Quit fiddling. Want the boat
running smooth when we get back.
Have faith, Captain.
Not today.
Pair of clips
in the rear hatch.
We should hit town right
during Sunday worship.
Won't be any crowds.
If Fanty and Mingo are
right about the payroll,
this could look to be
a sunny day for us.
SIMON: River, stay
behind the others.
If there's fighting, drop
to the floor or run away.
It's okay to leave
them to die.
Doctor, I'm taking your sister
under my protection here.
If anything happens to
her, anything at all,
I swear to you, I will
get very choked up.
Honestly.
There could be tears.
Don't mind the Captain none, Simon.
I know he'll look out for her.
They'll be back
before you can spit.
Well, not that you spit.
JAYNE: What are we hoping to find
here that equals the worth of a turd?
MAL: Security payroll. Alliance
don't have the manpower
to "enforce the peace"
on every outer-rim planet.
They hire out to the private firms,
who will not work for credit.
They get paid in cashy money,
which, once a month, rests here.
Don't that lead back to
the Alliance, anyhow?
No private firm would ever report
the theft of their own payroll.
They'd appear weak, might
lose their contract.
Yeah, we're as ghosts in this.
Won't but rattle the floor.
Shiny. Let's be bad guys.
Hands and knees and heads bowed down!
Everybody, down!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Looks like this
is the place.
You all wanna be looking very
intently at your own belly buttons.
I see a head start to rise,
violence is going to ensue.
Probably guessed we mean
to be thieving here,
but what we're after
is not yours.
So let's have
no undue fussing.
She's locked up.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
(GUN COCKS)
Do you know what the
definition of a hero is?
Someone who gets
other people killed.
You can look
it up later.
Big happy family.
(BEEPS)
At last. We can retire and
give up this life of crime.
(METAL RATTLING)
Hey!
You all are Browncoats, eh?
Fought for independence?
Petty thieving ain't
exactly soldiers' work.
War's long done. We're all
just folk now. Listen up!
We are coming down
to empty that vault!
GUARD: You have to give me
your authorization password!
(FIRING)
GUARD: Okay.
I'm telling you I heard it.
Repeater.
Did sound somewhat like gun blast.
Maybe you ought run tell Lawman.
(SCREAMING)
What the hell is up?
You all right?
What's going on?
Reavers.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
The leg is good. It'll bleed plenty
and we avoid any necessary organs.
I was thinking
more of a graze.
No, you don't want it to
look like you just gave up.
No, I get that.
JAYNE: Mal!
Every heist, he's got to
start yelling my name.
Mal! Reavers!
The girl's pitching a fit. They're
here or they're coming soon.
Get on the Mule.
Does that lock from the inside?
Yes.
Get everyone upstairs. You get
them down here and you seal it.
As long as you got air, you
don't open up, you understand?
But...
Get them inside
the vault!
You see them?
Zoe, take the wheel!
JAYNE: Anybody see them?
(ENGINE REVVING)
Take me with you!
Get back in the vault
with the others.
I can't stay here!
Please!
It's too many.
Move ahead.
Please!
(SCREAMING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(GRUNTING)
(ROARS)
(FIRING)
Faster! Faster! Faster
would be better!
How come they ain't
blowing us out the air?
They wanna run us down.
The up-close kill.
They want us alive
when they eat us.
Boy, sure would be nice if we had
some grenades, don't you think?
(GUN FIRING)
Wash, baby,
can you hear me?
We're moments from air.
You got somebody behind you?
Reavers.
(MURMURING)
Kaylee!
Heat her up.
We got Reavers.
(GASPS)
We're not gonna
get to you in time.
Keep moving, honey.
We're coming to you.
(FIRING)
JAYNE: Where's my clips?
Rear hatch.
(SCREAMING)
(YELLING)
Jayne!
I won't get ate!
You shoot me if they take me!
Well, don't shoot me first!
(GRUNTING)
Get some distance
on them.
You come to the flats, I
want you to swing round.
We're gonna try
a Barn Swallow.
Simon! Open her up!
MAL: They're closing on us!
Those rocks,
give them a taste.
WASH: Okay, baby,
we talked this through.
Talking ain't doing.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
(WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
River?
I swallowed a bug.
Are you okay?
(INDIGNANTLY) Is he okay?
WASH: We all here?
What's going on?
Hello?
No casualties.
Anybody following?
WASH: Nice flying, baby.
That's a negative.
Clean getaway.
Set course for Beaumonde. First
thing, I want this body...
KAYLEE: Simon!
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
You son of a whore.
I'm a hair's breadth
from riddling you
with holes, Doctor.
One simple job!
She'll be fine!
She is fine!
Except for being still crazy,
she's a picture of health!
Wasn't for River, we'd probably
be left there. She felt them coming.
Never again.
Do you understand me?
Seems I remember a talk about
you giving orders on my boat.
Well, we're
off your boat.
Just as soon as River gets
her share of the bounty.
Let's not do
anything hasty...
No, shiny!
We'll be on Beaumonde
in 10 hours' time,
you can pick up your earnings
and be on your merry.
Meantime, you
do your job.
Patch up my crew.
He didn't lie down.
They never lie down.
ZOE: No, I think things will
glide a deal smoother for us
without River and
Simon on board,
but how long do you
think they'll last?
Doc made his call.
Yeah.
They's as babes in a basket
when we took them in.
We sheltered
them plenty.
Man has to cut loose, learn
to stand on his own.
Like that man
back in town?
I had to shoot him.
What the Reavers would've done
to him before they killed him...
I know. That was
a piece of mercy.
But before that, him begging
us to bring him along.
We couldn't take the weight.
Would've slowed us down.
You know that
for certain?
Mule won't run
with five.
I should've dumped the girl?
Or you? Or Jayne?
Oh, Jayne...
You could've
tossed the payload.
Tossed the...
Zoe, I got bits falling off my ship,
I got a crew ain't been paid,
and,oh,yeah,a powerful need
to eat sometime this month.
We tell Fanty and Mingo
we skunked the job,
what do think
they'll do to us?
We're close to
gone out here.
We get a job,
we got to make good.
Sir, I don't disagree
on any particular point.
It's just,
in the time of war, we would've
never left a man stranded.
Maybe that's
why we lost.
That was close.
JAYNE: I do not get it.
How's a guy
get so wrong?
Cutting on his own face,
raping and murdering.
I'll kill a man
in a fair fight,
or if I think he's gonna
start a fair fight,
or if he bothers me,
or if there's a woman,
or if I'm getting paid. Mostly
only when I'm getting paid.
These Reavers,
the last 10 years,
they show up like the
bogeyman from stories.
Eating people alive?
Where does that get fun?
Shepherd Book said
they was men who just
reached the edge of space,
saw a vasty nothingness
and went bibbledy
over it.
Oh, hell.
(CLANKING)
JAYNE: I've been
to the edge.
Just looked like
more space.
I don't know.
It can get awful
lonely in the black.
Like to get
addlepated ourselves,
we stay on this
boat much longer.
Captain will drive us
all off, one by one.
Just like
Simon and River.
Just like Inara.
Kaylee, are you ever going
to put that capture down?
KAYLEE: We got to have records
of everything, Inara.
A bona fide companion entertained
clients on this very ship.
In this very bed.
Well, I can't do
my work here.
And I don't think
the Captain approves.
The Captain wants
you to stay...
That man doesn't know what he wants.
I don't have time to...
(MACHINERY WHINING)
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHATTERING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
WOMAN: Don't talk to the
barkers, talk to the captains.
You look the captain in the eye.
Know who you're dealing with.
I wish there was...
You shouldn't ought
to be so clean.
It's a dead giveaway you don't
belong, you always got to be tidy.
Don't pay anybody
in advance.
And don't ride in anything
with a Capissen 38 engine,
they fall right
out of the sky.
Kaylee.
River, do you want
to stay with them?
It isn't safe.
No.
I fear it isn't
safe anymore.
For them.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(MAN CHATTERING ON TV)
MAN ON TV: ...only survivors
of the massacre apparently
locked themselves in
the train station vault.
Kaylee, this is a place of business.
We can talk about Simon when...
When he's four
worlds away?
Or the Alliance gets a
hold of him and River?
MAL: That ain't my worry. I got to
finish this job and get us another one.
Can't do that
carrying those two.
KAYLEE: How can
you be so cold?
Captain didn't make
them fugitives.
But he could have
made them family.
Instead of keeping Simon
from seeing I was there.
When I carried such a
torch, when we could've...
Going on a year now, I ain't
had nothing twixt my nethers
weren't run
on batteries.
Oh, God!
I can't know that!
I could stand to
hear a little more.
If you had a care
for anybody's heart...
You knew he was
gonna leave.
We never been but a way
station to those two.
And how do you know
what he feels?
He's got River to worry on, but
he still could've shown you...
If I truly wanted
someone bad enough,
wouldn't be a thing in the 'verse
could stop me from going to her.
Tell that to Inara.
Domestic troubles?
'Cause we don't
wanna interrupt.
A man should keep
his house in order.
Fanty. Mingo.
He's Mingo.
He's Fanty.
You're Mingo.
(CHUCKLES)
How is it you
always know?
Fanty's prettier.
Feel to do
some business?
(ORIENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Endeavors.
(MAN CHATTERING ON TV)
MINGO: Quite a
crew you've got.
Yeah, they're a fine
bunch of reubens.
How you keep them on that
crap boat, is the subject
of much musing between
me and Fanty.
We go on and on.
So I'm noticing.
Is there a problem
we don't know of?
You got a sweet take
kissing your foot.
How's about you take your 25%,
we can talk about the next job?
Well, our end
is 40, precious.
My muscular buttocks
it's 40.
It is,
as of now.
Find anyone around
going cheaper...
going near
a sorry lot like you
in the first instance.
FANTY: You're
unpredictable, Mal.
You run when you
ought to fight.
Fight when you
ought to deal.
Makes a businessperson
a little twitchy.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(JINGLE PLAYING)
(SINGING) Fruity oaty bars
make a man of a mouse
Fruity oaty bars make you
bust out of your blouse
(SINGING JINGLE)
(DISTORTED VOICES CHATTERING)
Miranda.
(GROANING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
Hey! A tussle!
Jayne.
(ALARM BEEPING)
(GRUNTING)
Do you know
that girl?
I really don't.
(EXCLAIMING)
(GRUNTING)
Gorrammit, girl,
it's me!
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
(YELLING)
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
May I see her?
I believe you've got
some storytelling to do.
What in the hell
happened back there?
Start with the part where Jayne gets
knocked out by a 90-pound girl.
'Cause I don't think
that's ever getting old.
Do we know if
anyone was killed?
It's likely.
I know she meant to kill me
before the Doc put her out.
Which, how exactly
does that work anyhow?
It's a safe word.
The people who helped
me break River out
had intel that River and the
other subjects were being
embedded with behavioral
conditioning.
They taught me
a safe word,
in case something
happened.
Not sure I get it.
It's a phrase that
makes her fall asleep.
If I speak the words...
Don't say it!
It only works
on her, Jayne.
Well, now I know that.
In case something
happened?
You feel to elaborate on what
that something might be?
They never said what...
And you never did ask.
Get your hands off...
Eight months. Eight months,
you had her on my boat,
knowing full well she
could go monkeyshit
at the wrong word.
You never said a thing.
I brought her out here so
they couldn't get to her.
I don't even know
what they...
My ship!
My Crew!
You had a gorramn time
bomb living with us!
Who we gonna find in
there when she wakes up?
The girl?
Or the weapon?
I thought she was
getting better.
And I thought they
was getting off!
Didn't we have an intricate plan how
they was gonna be not here anymore?
We couldn't leave them now.
JAYNE: No, now that
she's a killer woman, we ought be
bringing her tea and dumplings.
In earnest, Mal, Why'd
you bring her back on?
May I see her?
She goes woolly again, we're gonna
have to put a bullet to her.
It's crossed my mind.
Can I make a suggestion that
doesn't involve violence,
or is this the
wrong crowd?
Honey.
We're flying a lot
blinder than usual here.
We need to get
our bearings.
I think we need to talk
to Mr. Universe.
(VOICES CHATTERING)
(STATIC CRACKLING)
Oh, this is good.
You guys always bring me
the very best violence.
You think you're
in a hot place?
That's what we're
looking to learn.
ls there any follow up,
a newswave?
There is no news. There's
the truth of the signal.
What I see. And there's
the puppet theater
the Parliament jesters foist
on the somnambulant public.
Well, what about this? Did
this make the puppet theater?
No, sir. And no
lawforce flags, either.
I had to go into the
security feed direct.
You can do that?
Can't stop the
signal, Mal.
Everything goes somewhere,
and I go everywhere.
Security feeds are
a traipse to access,
and I wasn't the
first one in.
This has prints on it.
So somebody else
has been fed this.
Zoe, you sultry minx, stop
falling in love with me.
You're just gonna
embarrass yourself.
I have a commitment
to my Lovebot.
It was a very beautiful ceremony.
Lenore wrote her own vows,
I cried like a baby,
a hungry, angry baby.
And she falls asleep.
Which, she would be sleepy.
Can you go back?
See if anybody spoke with
her before she acted up.
Made any kind of
contact with her.
(JINGLE PLAYING)
Miranda.
"Miranda"?
Go back further.
No.
MAL: Please.
(SINGING JINGLE)
(CHUCKLING) Mal,
you're very smart.
Someone is
talking to her.
The oaty bar?
Subliminal.
It's a subliminal message,
broadwaved to trigger her.
I've been seeing this code pop
up all over, the last few weeks.
It's Alliance and
it's high military.
They have gone to enormous
trouble to find your little friend.
And found her, they have.
Do you all know what
it is you're carrying?
They're afraid
of me.
I'm sorry.
They should be.
But I'll show
them. Oh, God.
(SHUSHING)
It's okay.
Hey, it's okay.
Show me off
like a dog.
Old men covered
in blood.
It never touched them, but
they're drowning in it.
I don't know what I'm saying.
I never know what I'm saying.
In the Maidenhead,
you said something.
When you were triggered,
do you remember?
The Captain saw you say
something on the feed.
Miranda.
Ask her.
Who is Miranda?
Am I talking
to Miranda now?
No.
Not right.
But I think when
they triggered you,
it somehow
brought this up.
This memory.
It isn't mine.
The memory,
it isn't mine.
And I shouldn't have to carry it.
It isn't mine.
Don't make me
sleep again.
I won't.
Put a bullet to me.
Bullet in the
brainpan, squish.
(SOBBING)
Don't say that.
Not ever.
We'll get through this.
Things are going to
get much, much worse.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(WATER RUNNING)
(CHATTERING)
MAL: Thanks for taking
us in again, Shepherd.
SHEPHERD: You got a plan?
Hiding ain't a plan?
It'll do you
for a spell.
And the folks here'll be
glad of the extra coin.
But the Alliance
will be coming.
They're after this girl
with a powerful will.
I look to hear the tromp
of their boots any moment.
You won't.
This isn't a palms-up
military run, Mal.
No reports broadwaved,
no warrants.
Much as they want her,
they want her hid.
That means
closed file.
Means an operative.
Which is trouble
you've not known.
I could have
left her there.
I had an out.
Hell, I had every
reason in the 'verse
to leave her lay
and haul anchor.
It's not your
way, Mal.
I have a way?
That better
than a plan?
Only one thing is gonna
walk you through this, Mal.
Belief.
You know I always look
to you for counsel,
but sermons make me
sleepy, Shepherd.
I ain't looking for
help from on high.
That's a long wait
for a train don't come.
When I talk about belief, why do you
always assume I'm talking about God?
They'll come at
you sideways.
It's how they think.
It's how they move.
Sidle up and smile. Hit
you where you're weak.
Sort of man they're like
to send believes hard.
Kills and never
asks why.
It's of interest to me how much you
seem to know about that world.
I wasn't born
a Shepherd, Mal.
Have to tell me
about that sometime.
(SIGHING)
No, I don't.
WOMAN: River?
River, you look tired.
I think everybody's a little tired by now.
Why don't we all lie down?
A little peace and quiet
will make everything better.
River. Do as
you're told.
No.
It's going to be
fine. Lie down.
No.
MAN: Cut them down.
(MUMBLING) What?
WASH: Mal! You up?
I got a wave. I'm gonna
bounce it down to you.
Inara.
I... Is this
a bad time?
No, it's good as any.
How's your world?
Cold. It's autumn here.
Still at the
Training House?
(CLEARING THROAT)
So, what occasions the wave?
Not that to see you ain't...
Well, you look very fine.
Oh. Thank you.
MAL: So, what was the...
I guess we're having something of
a problem here with the locals.
And, I thought
maybe...
You could use a gun hand?
I'm hoping not. But if you happen
to be close at all, you...
The crew could take your ease
here for a while. And there'd be payment.
Well, it would be...
I mean, I'd like to.
Kaylee's been missing
you something fierce.
ALL: Oh, man.
I miss her, too.
I even miss my shuttle,
occasionally.
Yeah, you left...
Got some of your
stuff in a trunk.
I never did get a
chance to drop it off.
(STAMMERING) I didn't
mean to leave stuff.
I didn't look
through the stuff.
I just... Just
sundries, I expect.
So I'll send you a
wave, soon as I can.
Thank you.
Inara, nice to
see her again.
So, trap?
Trap.
ZOE: We going in?
Only but a
few hours out.
Yeah, but, remember the
part where it's a trap?
If that's the case, then
Inara's already caught in it.
She wouldn't set
us up willing.
Might be we got a shot at seeing
who's turning these wheels.
We go in.
But how can you be sure Inara
don't just wanna see you?
Sometimes people
have feelings.
I'm referring
here to people.
You all were watching,
I take it.
Yes.
Did you see
us fight?
No.
Trap.
We're about 70 miles from the
Training House, and nobody on radar.
If the Alliance is about,
they're laying low.
They're about.
Find us a home. I'll take the
shuttle a little closer.
Zoe, ship
is yours.
Remember. If anything
happens to me,
or if you don't hear
from me within the hour,
you take this ship and you
come and you rescue me.
What?
Risk my ship?
I mean it.
It's cold out there. And
I don't wanna get left.
Dear Buddha, please bring me a
pony, and a plastic rocket, and...
Mal! What are
you doing here?
Well, you invited me.
I never thought for a second
you'd be stupid enough to come.
Well, that makes you kind
of a tease, doesn't it?
You knew my invitation
wasn't on the level.
Which led me to conclude that
you must be in some trouble.
I'm fine. I'm giddy.
For a woman schooled in telling
a man what he wants to hear,
you ain't much of a liar.
Mal, you cannot
handle this man.
I have to say, Captain,
I'm impressed that you would
come for her yourself.
And that you would make it
this far, in that outfit.
I can be very graceful
when I need to.
I've no doubt.
What are you doing?
I'm praying for you, Mal.
She's very thoughtful.
But I mean it when I say
I've no intent to harm you.
Speak your piece.
I think you're beginning
to understand
how dangerous River Tam is.
She is a mite
unpredictable.
Mood swings,
of a sort.
It's worse
than you know.
It usually is.
That girl will rain destruction
down on you and your ship.
She is an albatross,
Captain.
Way I remember it,
albatross was a ship's good luck,
till some idiot killed it.
Yes, I've read a poem.
Try not to faint.
I've seen your
war record.
I know how you must
feel about the Alliance.
You really don't.
Fair to say.
But I have to hope you
understand, you can't beat us.
I got no need
to beat you.
I just want
to go my way.
And you can do that,
once you let me take
River Tam back home.
No, no. You're working
this deal all crabbed.
You got to open
with payment.
That is a trap.
I offer money, you'll play the
man of honor and take umbrage.
I ask you to do what is right,
you'll play the brigand.
I have no stomach
for games.
I already know you
will not see reason.
The Alliance wanted
to show me a reason,
they shouldn't have
sent an assassin.
I have a warship in
deep orbit, Captain.
We locked on to Serenity's pulse
beacon the moment you hit atmo.
I can speak a word
and send a missile
to that exact location
inside of three minutes.
You do that,
you'd best make peace with
your dear and fluffy lord.
Pulse beacon.
Advice from an old tracker. You want
to find someone, use your eyes.
How long do you think you
can really run from us?
I never credited the Alliance
with an overabundance of brains.
And if you're
the best they got...
Captain Reynolds,
I should tell you, so that
you don't waste your time,
you can't make me angry.
Please, spend
an hour with him.
I want to resolve this
like civilized men.
I'm not
threatening you.
I'm unarmed.
Good.
I am, of course, wearing
full body armor.
I am not a moron.
INARA: Wait, just let...
(GRUNTING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
(GASPING)
What, no backup?
Making an awful ruckus.
They'll come when
they're needed.
I'd start whistling.
Captain, what do you think
is going to happen here?
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(RIPPING)
(CLATTERING)
(GROANING)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(PANTING)
Nothing here is what it seems.
He isn't the plucky hero.
The Alliance isn't some evil empire.
This is not the grand arena.
And that's not incense.
(BEEPING)
Sir, can you hear me?
Just a flash bomb.
Go. Go!
(INARA AND MAL GRUNTING)
What have you done
to my shuttle?
It's not your shuttle.
Head east. Keep her low.
(ENGINE REVVING)
Okay, forget the
pulse beacon.
There must be another
way to track the ship.
Get a read on
the nav. sat.
It's a registered transport,
you must be able to locate.
ENSIGN: Sir?
Yes, have you found
a nav. sat. trajectory?
Sir, we found seven.
INARA: We've every
reason to be afraid.
Why, 'cause this guy beat up Mal?
That ain't so hard.
He didn't beat me up.
Nobody said that.
Because he's a believer.
He's intelligent, methodical,
and devout in his belief
that killing River is
the right thing to do.
So no hope of
a reward, huh?
Did he say anything
about a Miranda?
What is that?
Don't know who or what,
but it's on River's mind.
Conjure it might be the
reason they're after her.
You think maybe it poses some
kind of threat to the Alliance?
Do we care?
Are we caring
about that?
You dumb-ass hogs, the only
people she's a threat to is
us on this boat.
Look, we get back to Haven
in a few hours' time.
Oh, yeah. Hiding under
the Shepherd's skirts
that's a manful scheme.
You wanna run
this ship?
Yes.
Well, you can't.
Do a damn sight
better job than you.
Getting us lashed over
a couple of strays.
No offense, Doc. I think
it's noble as a grape,
the way you
look to River.
But she ain't my sister
and she ain't your crew.
Oh, and neither is
she exactly helpless.
So where's it writ that we got
to lay down our lives for her?
Which is what you've
steered us toward.
I didn't start this.
No, that's right.
Alliance starts the war,
and then you volunteer.
Battle of Serenity, Mal.
Besides Zoe here, how many...
Hey, I'm talking at you.
How many men in your platoon
came out of there alive?
You wanna leave this room.
Damn right, I do.
This isn't
the war, Mal.
You telling me that 'cause
you think I don't know?
You came to the Training
House looking for a fight.
I came looking
for you.
I just want to know
who I'm dealing with.
I've seen too many versions
of you to be sure.
I start fighting a war, I guarantee
you'll see something new.
We'll get off.
River and I will
get off at Haven.
We'll find some...
Nobody's saying that.
Nobody besides Jayne
is saying that.
Mal.
I got no answers for you, Inara.
I got no rudder.
Wind blows northerly, I go north.
That's who I am.
Now maybe that ain't a man to
lead, but they have to follow.
So you wanna
tear me down,
do it inside
your own mind.
I'm not trying
to tear you down.
But you fog things up.
You always have.
You spin me about.
I wish like hell
you was elsewhere.
(SIGHS)
I was.
(RUMBLING)
(FLIES BUZZING)
(GASPS)
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
(BEEPING)
No trouble,
little crazy person.
We're going for
a nice shuttle ride.
(GUN FIRES)
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
She's out. Jayne's down.
The other way. Find her
and do not engage.
(BEEPING)
It's gonna be okay...
(COUGHS)
She's sealed off the bridge.
I do not like her there.
Check the shuttle. She
could have snuck in.
Captain.
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
The government's man, he
says you're a danger to us.
Not worth helping.
Is he right?
Are you anything
but a weapon?
I've staked my crew's life on
the theory you're a person,
actual and whole, and if I'm
wrong, you'd best shoot me now.
(CLICKS)
Or we could talk more.
Miranda.
How can it be there's a
whole planet called Miranda
and none of us
knowed that?
Because there isn't one.
It's a blackrock. Uninhabitable.
Terraforming didn't hold, or some such.
Few settlers died.
ZOE: Was it right
before the war?
I had to show them. I didn't know
if you were going to make me sleep.
You could
have asked.
KAYLEE: Wait
a tick, yeah.
Some years back, there was call
for workers to settle on Miranda.
Daddy talked about it. Nothing
about it on the Cortex.
History, Astronomy,
it's not in there.
Half of writing history
is hiding the truth.
There's something on that rock
the Alliance doesn't want known.
That's right at the edge of
the Burnham Quadrant, right?
Furthest planet out? It's
not that far from here.
Whoa. No. No. Honey...
That's a bad notion.
...you show them the bad.
I got it, baby.
This is us, at Haven,
and here's Miranda.
All along here, that empty space in
between, that's Reaver territory.
They just float out there,
sending out raiding parties.
ZOE: Nobody ventures there.
Not even the Alliance.
You go through that, you're
signing up to be a banquet.
I'm on board with our standard
run-and-hide scenario.
And we are just about...
Wait.
JAYNE: Doesn't
look like Reavers.
Wasn't.
KAYLEE: Shepherd?
Shepherd?
KAYLEE: Shepherd Book?
(COCKING GUN)
(MAN COUGHING)
Get the Doc.
Shepherd.
(GASPING)
Don't move.
Won't go far.
Shouldn't have
been you.
Alliance should've hit
us. Should've hit me.
That crossed my mind.
(COUGHING)
I shot him down.
Yeah. I see.
I killed the ship
that killed us.
Not very Christian of me.
You did what's right.
Coming from you, that
means almost nothing.
(COUGHING)
I'm long gone.
No, Doc will
bring you around.
I look to be bored by many
more sermons before you slip.
Just don't move.
Can't order me
around, boy.
I'm not one
of your crew.
Yes, you are.
River...
Come on.
Hey.
I don't care what you believe.
Just believe it.
Whatever you...
How come they
ain't waiting?
They knowed we was coming,
how come they only sent one?
They didn't know
we were coming here.
Get on the Cortex.
Wave, Li Shen,
the Sanchez brothers,
anyone who has ever
sheltered us after a heist.
Tell them to get out.
Get out now.
I'm sorry.
If your quarry goes to ground,
leave no ground to go to.
You should have
taken my offer.
Or did you think none
of this was your fault?
I don't murder children.
I do.
If I have to.
Why'?
Do you even know
why they sent you?
It's not my
place to ask.
I believe in something
greater than myself.
A better world.
A world without sin.
So me and mine gotta
lay down and die
so you can live in
your better world?
I'm not going to live there.
There's no place
for me there
any more than there
is for you. Malcolm,
I'm a monster.
What I do is evil.
I have no illusions about
it, but it must be done.
Keep talking.
You're not getting a location
trace off this wave.
And every minute you keep River Tam
from me, more people will die.
You think I care?
Of course you care.
You're not a Reaver, Mal.
You're a human man and you
will never understand how...
Get these bodies together.
ZOE: We got time
for grave digging?
Zoe, you and Simon
rope them together.
Five or six of them. I want them
laid out on the nose of our ship.
Are you insane? I won't
desecrate these bodies.
I don't understand. What
do you mean, the bodies...
I want you to muck up
the reactor core.
Just enough to leave a trail
and make it read like
we're flying without containment,
not enough to fry us.
These people are our friends.
Kaylee,
you got a day's work to do
and two hours to do it.
Jayne, you and Wash hoist up
the cannon mount. Goes right on top.
Piece or two of the other
ship, stick it on.
Any place you can tear hull without
inner breach, do that, too.
We're gonna need paint.
We're gonna need red paint.
Sir,
do you really mean to turn
our home into an abomination
so that we can make
a suicidal attempt
at passing through
Reaver space?
I mean to live.
(MAN COUGHING)
I mean for us to live.
The Alliance won't have that, so
we go where they don't follow.
God's balls, there ain't no
way we're going out there.
Think about what
you're asking.
JAYNE: Those Reavers'll
eat us alive...
This is how it is.
Anybody doesn't wanna
fly with me anymore,
this is your port
of harbor.
There's a lot of
fine ways to die.
I ain't waiting for the
Alliance to choose mine.
I mean to confound these bungers.
Take my shot at getting to Miranda.
Maybe find something I can
use to get clear of this.
So I hear a word out of any of
you that ain't helping me out
or taking your leave,
I will shoot you down.
Get to work.
ZOE: Sir...
Just tell me
when we're close.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
MAL: Wash.
Define "disappeared."
ZOE: Every reading
I'm getting says normal.
Oceans, land masses. No tectonic
instability or radiation.
Yeah, but no
power, either.
Nothing at all?
Wait.
Something.
It might be a beacon,
but it's awful weak.
Find it.
Gravity's Earthnorm.
O2 levels check,
pressure...
If anything's wrong the
scanner's not reading it.
Well, something sure
the hell ain't right.
This ain't no
little settlement.
We flew over at least a
dozen cities just as big.
Why didn't we ever
hear about this?
(BEEPING)
Beacon's up ahead.
Ho.
No entry wounds,
fractures.
Poison?
Got another one.
They's just
sitting here.
They didn't crash.
(MALE ANNOUNCER CHATTERING)
Kaylee. Don't...
(SCREAMS)
How come these ones
are preserved?
Place must've gone hermetic
when the power blew.
Sealed them.
KAYLEE: What are
they doing?
What's everybody doing?
There's no unusual
discoloration.
Nobody's doubled over
or showing signs of pain.
MAL: There's gasses that
kill painless, right?
They didn't fall.
None of them.
They just lay down.
(RIVER MUTTERING IN CHINESE)
Make them stop.
They're everywhere.
Every city, every...
Every house, every room,
they're all inside me.
I can hear them all, and
they're saying nothing!
Get up.
Please get up.
(SPEAKING CHINESE)
Please, God,
make me a stone.
She is starting
to damage my calm.
ZOE: Jayne.
She's right!
Everybody's dead.
This whole world is
dead for no reason!
Let's get to
the beacon.
WASH: This is the source?
JAYNE: This ship's
banged up all to hell.
These are just a few of
the images we've recorded.
And you can see
it isn't what we thought.
There's been no war here,
and no terraforming event.
The environment is stable.
It's the Pax.
The G-23 Paxilon Hydroclorate
that we added to the air processors.
It was supposed to calm the
population, weed out aggression.
Well, it works.
The people here
stopped fighting.
And then they stopped
everything else.
They stopped going to work,
they stopped breeding,
talking, eating.
There's 30 million people here, and
they all just let themselves die.
(CRASHING)
(GASPS)
I have to be quick.
About a tenth of
a percent of
the population had the
opposite reaction to the Pax.
Their aggressor response
increased beyond madness.
They have become...
(CRASHING)
Well, they've killed
most of us.
And not just killed,
they've done things.
Reavers. They
made them.
I won't live to report this,
but people have to know.
We meant it
for the best,
to make people safer.
(REAVERS GROWLING)
God!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(REAVER GROWLING)
Turn it off.
(SOBBING)
(RETCHING)
River.
I'm all right.
MAL: This report is
maybe 12 years old.
Parliament buried it, and it stayed
buried till River dug it up.
This is what they
feared she knew.
And they were
right to fear,
because there's a whole universe of
folk who are gonna know it, too.
They're gonna see it.
Somebody has to speak
for these people.
You all got on this boat
for different reasons,
but you all come
to the same place.
So now I'm asking more of
you than I have before.
Maybe all.
Sure as I know anything I know
this, they will try again.
Maybe on another world, maybe on
this very ground swept clean.
A year from now, 10, they'll
swing back to the belief
that they can
make people
better.
And I do not
hold to that.
So no more running.
I aim to misbehave.
Shepherd Book
used to tell me,
"if you can't do
something smart,
do something right."
Do we have a plan?
Mr. Universe.
We haven't the equipment
to broadwave this code,
but he can put it on every
screen for 30 worlds.
He's pretty damn close, too.
We still got
the Reavers
and probably the Alliance,
between us and him.
JAYNE: That's two armies
against our one bitty cannon.
It's a fair bet the Alliance
knows about Mr. Universe.
They're gonna
see this coming.
No.
They're not gonna
see this coming.
(ENGINE REVVING)
No problem. Bring it on.
Bring it on. Bring it on.
From here to the eyes and
ears of the 'verse. That's my motto,
or it might be, if I
start having a motto.
We won't be long.
You're going to get caught
in the ion cloud.
It'll play merry hob
with your radar,
but pretty lights and a few miles
after, you'll be right in my orbit.
You'll let us know if
anyone else comes at you?
You'll be the first.
There.
Toss me my 30 coin, but I
got a news wave for you...
(GRUNTING)
Call in every ship in the quadrant.
We'll meet them in the air.
Destroy it all.
MAL: Wash, we
almost through?
Now!
WASH: Go! Move!
I'm reading activity
in the cloud.
Lock and fire
on my command.
You should have let
me see her, Captain.
We should have done this as men.
Not with fire.
HELMSMAN: Sir.
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
Vessel in range.
Lock on.
Bastard's not even
changing course.
Sir!
Target the Reavers.
Target the Reavers!
Target everyone!
Somebody fire!
I am a leaf on the wind.
Watch how I soar.
Chicken's come
home to roost.
MAL: The hell?
It's okay.
I am a leaf on the wind!
What does that mean?
We're almost through.
Yes! Yes! No! No! No!
(RUMBLING)
We're not alone.
EMP!
Everybody, strap
yourselves into something!
Jayne.
Got it.
Kaylee, come on.
We're fried.
I got no control.
Where's the backup?
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(EXPLOSIONS)
Check! Check!
(ENGINE WHINING)
(JAYNE SCREAMING)
(WHOOSHING)
(RUMBLING)
MAL: Get up!
KAYLEE: Stop it!
Backup reads at 20%.
Can you get us down?
I'm going to have
to glide her in.
Will that work?
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
I am a leaf on the wind.
Watch how...
(GASPS)
Wash, baby. Baby, no. Baby, come on.
You gotta go. Come on.
We gotta move. Baby, please.
We gotta move, baby, come on.
MAL: Zoe!
Move out! Now!
Go. Go.
Head inside!
Jayne, rearguard.
Zoe, what've we got?
ZOE: Sir,
this is a good
hold point.
We all stay together.
No.
They have to come
through here.
They'll bottleneck,
we can thin them out.
We get pushed back,
there's the blast doors.
I can rig them so they won't
reopen once they close.
Shut them and
hide until I get...
We need to draw
them till it's done.
This is the place.
We'll buy you the time.
All right, let's move these
crates back there for cover.
Make sure they ain't filled
with nothing goes boom.
Wait, Wash!
Where's Wash?
He ain't coming.
Move the gorramn crates!
(REAVERS HOWLING)
Tell me you brought
them this time.
(REAVERS GROWLING)
(EXPLOSION)
(GRUNTING)
Zoe?
Are you here?
Do the job, sir.
You hold. Hold
till I get back.
Captain's right.
Can't be thinking on revenge if
we're gonna get through this.
Do you really think any of us
are gonna get through this?
I might.
(STATIC CRACKLING)
No.
Mal.
Guy killed me, Mal.
He killed me with a sword.
How weird is that?
I got a short span here.
They destroyed
my equipment,
but I have
a backup unit.
Bottom of the complex,
right over the generator.
Hard to get to.
I know they missed it.
They can't stop
the signal, Mal.
They can never
stop the signal.
(REAVERS GROWLING)
The Reavers. They are
all made up of rage.
It's okay.
(SHUSHING)
I can't shut them up.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Stay low.
She picked a sweet bung of a
time to go helpless on us.
Jayne and I take
the first wave.
Nobody shoots unless
they get past our fire.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
I didn't plan on
going out like this.
I think we did
right, but...
No. I never
planned anything.
I just wanted to
keep River safe.
Spent so much time on
Serenity ignoring anything
that I wanted
for myself.
My one regret
in all of this
is never being with you.
With me?
You mean to say, as...
Sex?
I mean to say.
(METAL SQUEAKS)
Hell with this.
I'm gonna live.
Mal. Guy killed me, Mal.
He killed me with a sword.
(REAVERS GROWLING)
(BANGING)
"Hard to get to."
That's a fact.
(GROWLING)
Zoe, gorrammit!
(REAVERS SHRIEKING)
(GRUNTING)
Zoe, get your ass
back on the line!
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
You shot me in the back!
I haven't made you
angry, have I?
There are a lot of innocent people
in the air being killed right now.
You have no idea
how true that is.
I know the secret.
The truth that burned
up River Tam's brain.
Rest of the 'verse is going
to know it, too. 'Cause they need to.
Do you really believe that?
I do.
You willing to die
for that belief?
I am.
(GRUNTING)
Of course, that ain't
exactly Plan A.
(GROANING)
Spine's intact.
Just give me a bandage.
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SOBBING)
JAYNE: Up high, left!
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
Kaylee!
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
Fall back! Everybody, fall back!
Fall back now!
Jayne, grenade.
Very last one.
They're gonna get in.
I can close it
from the outside.
No one's coming
back from that.
How much ammo
do we have?
Three, four max,
and my swinging cod. That's all.
The lift isn't moving.
When they come, try to
plug the hole with it.
I'm starting to lose
some feeling here.
Lie still. I'm going
to give you something...
My bag.
(GUN FIRES)
(GUN FIRING)
Keep pressure here.
SIMON: My bag.
I need
adrenaline and a shot of
calaphar for Kaylee.
I can't.
River.
River, I'm sorry.
No.
I hate to leave.
You won't.
You take care
of me, Simon.
You've always
taken care of me.
My turn.
(GRUNTING)
(OPERATIVE AND MAL GRUNTING)
Do you know what
your sin is, Mal?
Hell. I'm a fan
of all seven.
(GRUNTING)
But right now,
I'm going to have
to go with wrath.
We ain't got long.
(THUDDING)
You suppose he
got through?
Do you think Mal
got the word out?
He got through. I
know he got through.
(GROANS)
(COUGHS)
I'm sorry.
You should know there's
no shame in this.
You've done
remarkable things.
But you're
fighting a war
you've already lost.
(GROANS)
(GASPING)
Well, I'm known for that.
(GROANING)
Piece of shrapnel tore up that
nerve cluster my first tour.
Had it moved.
Sorry about the throat.
Expect you'd want to say your
famous last words right now.
Just one trouble.
I ain't gonna kill you.
(GASPING)
Hell, I'm gonna grant
your greatest wish.
(BEEPING)
I'm gonna show you
a world without sin.
These are just a few of the
few images we've recorded.
And you can see
it isn't what we thought.
There's been no war here,
and no terraforming event.
The environment is stable.
It's the Pax.
The G-23 Paxilon Hydroclorate
that we added to the air processors.
It was supposed to
calm the population...
(ROARING)
We meant it for the best,
to make people safer.
(REAVERS GROWLING)
God!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
Sir?
It's done.
Report.
River?
(CLANKING)
SOLDIER 1: Drop your weapons!
SOLDIER 2: Do it now.
Weapons down.
Let it down, now.
I want to see your
hands in the air.
Stand down.
Do it.
Targets are acquired.
Do we have a kill order?
Do we have an order?
THE OPERATIVE: Stand down.
Stand down. It's finished.
We're finished.
THE OPERATIVE: It's
not over, you know.
I can't guarantee that
they won't come after you.
The Parliament.
Your broadwave about Miranda
has weakened their regime.
They are not gone and
they are not forgiving.
That don't bode
especially well for you,
giving the order to let us
go, patching up our hurt.
I told them the Tams were no
longer a threat, damage done.
They might listen,
but I think they know
I'm no longer their man.
They take you down, I don't
expect to grieve over much.
Like to kill you myself,
I see you again.
You won't.
There is nothing
left to see.
Sir, we have
a green light.
Inspection's pos and we're
clear for up-thrust.
Think she'll
hold together?
She's tore up plenty.
But she'll fly true.
Make sure
everything's secure.
Could be bumpy.
Always is.
Taking her out.
Should be about a day's ride
to get you back to your girls.
Right.
Ready to get off this heap,
back to civilized life?
I...
I don't know.
Good answer.
So you gonna ride shotgun
with me, help me fly?
That's the plan.
Think you can
work out...
(ENGINE REVVING)
Okay.
Clearly some aptitude
for the...
it ain't all buttons and
charts, little albatross.
You know what the first
rule of flying is?
Well, I suppose you do, since you
already know what I'm about to say.
I do.
But I like to
hear you say it.
Love.
You can learn all the
math in the 'verse,
but you take a boat in the
air that you don't love,
she'll shake you off just as
sure as the turn of the worlds.
Love keeps her in the air
when she ought to fall down,
tells you she's hurting
before she keels.
Makes her a home.
(RAIN PATTERING)
Storm's getting worse.
We'll pass through
it soon enough.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
MAL: What was that?